Prateek Singh

Product Designer

A designer by passion and education. I have been working as a Lead UX Designer at Wongdoody since after completing my Master's in 2020. I have a knack for Tech and my academics and work experiences have provided me with just the right tools to humanize it.

\mathbf{M}

sprateek0204@gmail.com



www.prateeksingh.in



9711960199 | 8467884193

SKILLS

Interaction Design, Strategic Design, Research Method & Processes, Prototyping, Information Architecture, User Journey Mapping, Accessibility, Usability testing

TOOLS

Figma

Adobe XD

Photoshop

HTML5

CSS3

JavaScript

Microsoft Office

Premiere Pro

RECOGNITION

Wongdoody Insta Award

Awarded for my contribution in a high demand client work.

Full Stack Designer

Completed a demanding training to earn the above certificate.

Infosys Certified Digital Accessibility Associate.

HOBBIES

Blogging

Cycling

Cricket

3D Printing

Esports

WORK EXPERIENCE

Wongdoody | Infosys

JAN 2021 — PRESENT

Lead Experience Designer

Worked with multiple Fortune 500 clients, designing across a variety of domains. Meanwhile, continuously skilling up through the in-house trainings and initiatives.

· US Based tech giant

Working with a team of designers to create, maintain and update a major sales portal and system of products around it. Lead multiple verticals from conception to realization.

South Korean Multinational Conglomerate

Lead two verticals within the project. Designed 10+ standalone widgets and the web-interface for a call tracker API. Received a 94% approval rate from client.

· Dashboard for Logistics Company

Designed and presented native flows for a white-label product.

Freelance Designer

JUL 2018- DEC 2020

Worked across multiple design domains including UX, architecture, branding and Industrial Design. The clientele being mostly early stage startups e.g., ORIS & SOMA.

INTERNSHIPS

Evinix Design Concepts Pvt Ltd, Ghaziabad

JUN 2019 - JUL 2019

Product Design Intern

Designed and prototyped 3 articles which later made into mass-manufacturing. Documented the entire process and presented to the graduating class of M.Des students.

Spacematters, Delhi

JAN 2017 - JUL 2017

Research and Documentation Intern

Interviewed 30+ people and documented several processes of a native wood craft — likhai. Co-authored the only comprehensive document existing for the apparently lost wood craft.

Delhi Development Authority

JAN 2014 - JUL 2014

Transportation Design Intern

Researched vehicular density and conducted traffic analysis along a proposed route in Delhi. Later, worked with Transport Planners to design and develop the said corridors and presented the design to the Lieutenant Governor of Delhi.

EDUCATION

Special Program for Strategic Insights

MAR 2022 - PRESENT

Center of Complexity
Rhode Island School of Design

M.Des | Industrial and Product Design

2020

Department of Industrial Design,

School of Planning and Architecture, New Delhi — First Class with Distinction

Bachelor of Architecture (B.Arch)

2018

School of Planning and Architecture, New Delhi - First Class

HSC, CBSE

Delhi Public School, Lucknow 89.3%